Philipp Welsch

pwelsch86@gmail.com

Software

Homepage

Engineer

LinkedIn

In a nutshell

I'm a programmer who acts as a generalist with a strong interest in computer graphics. My experience ranges from game engine development for PC and consoles over VR development to maintaining front- and back-end systems for customer- and user-facing applications.

Experience

Playground Games / Systems Programmer

March 2019 - Present, Leamington Spa, England

Working as Systems Engineer on an unannounced AAA project at Playground Games, an Xbox Games Studio.

d3t LTD / Junior Core Tech Programmer

January 2018 - March 2019, Cheshire, England

- Building and maintaining high-performance systems written in C++ and C.
 Optimizing titles for both CPU and GPU side performance.
- Rendering and Xbox One platform support for a major UE4 title.

Polycular OG / Intern Programmer

July 2016 - December 2016, Hallein, Austria

- Designed, implemented and maintained core libraries used across multiple projects with Unity on iOS, Android and PC.
- Implemented core frameworks, game logic and and user interfaces for Alternate Reality and location-based experiences.

Major League Gladiators / Lead Student Developer

November 2016 - April 2018, Global

A multiplayer VR coop FPS for HTC Vive built with Unreal Engine 4.

- Designed and implemented systems for other programmers to build upon
- Extended and maintained a custom build of Unreal Engine 4.

Education

FH Salzburg / BSc with honors, Multimediatechnology

September 2014 - July 2017, Salzburg, Austria

Computer Science with a major focus on software engineering, game programming and image processing. **Thesis**: Exploring the Applicability of Data-Oriented Design to Scene Graphs for Rendering